In today's video, I'm going to be
ranking every single Meta Ads creative
format from the god-like S-tier ads that
almost always turn into unicorn scaling
ads down to the F-tier ones that you
probably even shouldn't [music] be
wasting your budget on. I spent the last
10 years growing brands using Meta Ads,
and I've been a part of making 20,000 ad
creatives on the teams that I've served.
So, I've developed some pretty big
opinions on what brand should really
focus on versus what they shouldn't be
wasting any of their budget on. So,
let's go ahead and dive in. First up, we
have AI animation ads. This is the big
one that I feel I came out of the
woodwork this year that initially
garnered a lot of attention because of
how fun and childlike it is. And what
I'll say, too, is there's multiple
different types of formats of these,
right? There's the Pixar animation style
ads, there's the claymation style ads,
there's like 10 different types of ads.
But, for [music] this one, I'm going to
say that it actually firmly fits into
the C-tier. Why? Well, number one, it's
a little bit more operationally complex.
You're going to really have to train
your team to develop a new school to
make these ads. And as far as actually
scaling brands, while I do find that a
lot of times these ones will hit a
pocket of a net new audience and scale
up really well initially, they don't
often become a long-term performing ad.
So, that's why I'm going to be a little
harsh and keep them in the C-tier.
[music] Now, the next one is going to be
the amateur investigation ad. Now, this
is one that I'm very proud of because I
like to think that my team really
brought this to popularity over the last
few months, and I'm going to give this
an A-tier. When we've developed this for
brands, it really scales up [music] well
and nicely. Now, the breakdown of this
ad is that essentially, you're going to
be hiring a creator to conduct an
amateur investigation on your product or
niche. In this one, we did someone who
is visiting different car dealerships.
And then next up we have the TikTok love
letter. I'm going to put this in a solid
B because they think it's number one
really easy to execute. And if you
already know the messaging and the
persona really well for your brand,
these can often be a really quick hit.
But it's not quite in that A or S tier
because I don't often find that this is
the ultimate unicorn type of scaling ad.
Very similarly, going to put this in the
same level actually is going to be the
real short. Now, both of these are
actually very top of funnel. So, what
I'll often find is maybe they're in the
top eight of top performing creatives,
but they're not going to be the thing
that makes or breaks a brand's overall
ad performance or can, you know,
necessarily transform a business
overnight. But it can often help really
develop the creative [music] ecosystem
further for a new type of concept or
persona that you really want to scale
into. So, I love thinking of these two
ads as supporting characters. And then
next up you got your yapper ads. Ooh,
I'm going to give this one an A tier.
Again, not quite in that S tier because
I think that it's actually very hard to
nail. And you have to make sure that you
have the right creator. And what the
creator is going to be doing is
essentially just yapping to camera,
right? It sort of feels easy cuz it's
like, "Oh, okay." All that you got to do
is have someone sit down, yap to cam,
talk about your product or a problem
that they have, and really dive into
their own personal storytelling. But I
find that it's very hard to actually
find these creators. But once you do,
it's going to be in that A tier. And
very often, these are going to scale up
really nicely if you can get the right
combination of the script and the
creator and the setting. [music] And
then we have our David and Goliath ads.
This is going to be another one that I'm
going to put as the A
This is another ad that we've seen scale
up super super nicely. And essentially,
this ad is a play on the David and
Goliath fable. So, the way that I like
to think about this for ad creative,
you're going to be positioning your
brand as David who is overcoming a big
industry or obstacle. And that
storytelling is often what is going to
get people to want to root for you and
the brand. At the agency, we
specifically use Storyblocks to help
tell the story of these David and
Goliath ads. And a huge thanks to
Storyblocks for sponsoring this video.
They are long-term friends of this
channel. They are a 100% human-made
stock library that is perfect for
combining with your creator content and
any other type of content that you might
have in your arsenal. Now, for the David
and Goliath ad specifically, when we are
trying to really visualize the Goliath
in the story, this is where Storyblocks
has really come to save the day for us
multiple times because it combines so
well with our creator and Sounders
content when we are making the specific
[music] ad. And my team really loves it
because it plugs right into Adobe
Creative Cloud and allows them to search
for assets directly inside of Premiere
Pro and After Effects. The reason why
over 150,000 creators and businesses use
Storyblocks is because it is 100%
royalty-free even for ads. To get access
to the human-made stock media library
built for creators and essential to my
workflow, head to
storyblocks.com/daradenni.
They're offering 15% off for a super
limited time and it is only available in
my link in the description below. Ooh,
and then we have number seven, the grid
style [music] statics. I love these. In
fact, one of my top-performing creatives
at the big nine-figure brand that I was
at, this was a grid style static.
[music]
And I love because it is so easy to
create, but if you have multiple
products and multiple SKUs, it can often
be a winner. So, I'm going to go ahead
and put this firmly in the A tier. I
have seen it become the top-performing
unicorn scaling ad for a handful of
brands, but I really think that there's
a little bit of storytelling often
missing for those, but if you have
bundle-based products and again multiple
SKUs, it is one of those low-hanging
fruit types of ad creatives that you
really really need to test. And then we
have EGC or employee-generated
content. often find that brands who do
this really really well are like Oats
Overnight, especially in their
warehouse, or Cheers Health, who has
actually got a lot more of their
employees to start doing content after
the success of their founders' content.
This is one that I'm going to put into
the B tier. Yikes, I often don't see it
scale up as nicely as founders' content,
and it can be a little operationally
complex getting your employees to
balance the duties of their actual
day-to-day like job description, plus
>> [music]
>> making content. find that the content
falls on the wayside unless it is
actually a part of their job
description. And then we have founders'
content. I'm going to go ahead and
automatically put this in the S tier
because I find that regardless of what
type of founders' content you do,
whether it is super high-five big
production [music] or it's low-fi just
with your phone, what I love about this
ad format is that if you can tell the
story about why you are making your
brand and why it is important to you,
you are going to automatically connect
with your audience, particularly if they
have that same type of problem or issue
that you do. It is like the number one
way to get [music] this done, and I
often find it is the first type of top
performer that a brand has. So,
founders' ads for the win for me. All
right, and then we have text-only ads.
You know what? I'm feeling a little
nervous doing this now because I'm like,
"Oh my goodness, I have shown you guys a
number of these formats throughout the
years." And I feel like some of you are
going to be mad at me being like, "You
said that we had to test this." Formats
go in and out of style, you know, but
this is one text-only ad that uh I'm
going to give it like my first negative
ranking, which is an E tier. Yes, I have
seen this do well for brands,
particularly actually like another one
that I'm going to mention, which is
technically text-only base, a founder's
letter. I have seen that perform really
well, especially during sales periods,
but this is one that I find people end
up not executing well because they're
using AI to write all the copy and it
just comes out bland. So, text-only ads,
you know, we live in a very visual
society on social media, so this is one
that unless you're using it for sales,
might be one to skip for now. Ooh, and
then callout ads. You know what? I I
really love a good callout ad, so I am
going to give this a B tier. This is one
actually that I find can scale up pretty
nicely if you already have a really good
idea of the type of messaging, angles,
or big creative concepts that are
working for you. If you decide to create
an iteration with a callout ad, this is
one that I have seen even in the last
few months still making moves and doing
really well. So, callout ads for the
win. And then we have the before and
afters. Ooh, I'm going to give this one
a B tier. This is one that I often find
again can be a really good supporting
cast member in your creative ecosystem,
but isn't actually going to be the one
to like puncture and convert net new
audiences and really offer that scale.
Sometimes it is the one though that's
going to convert really well for your
audience that's a little bit more
mid-funnel. And then very similar to
your before and after ads, we're going
to have your progression ads. [music]
Now, this can show a before and after
visual, but really what it's about, it's
about showing the progression over a
specific amount of time and the type of
results that your customers can
anticipate. And I'm actually going to
give this the exact same ranking as a
before and after. Again, a really good
supporting cast member for converting
people that are already in your
mid-funnel, but very likely not really
going to help you find net new
audiences. Ooh, and then we have press
ads. I'm going to give this one an F,
and I'll tell you why. I used to be a
huge champion of this type of ad format
years ago. I mean, I've been doing
YouTube now for like 7 years, but like 6
years ago I used to talk about press ads
and really talk about how it provided
the stamp of eligibility. The reason why
it's an F now is because they are a to
get permissions for. You know, if you do
get written up in Vogue, but then you
make a meta ad that has Vogue in it,
unless you're just using the logo, but
if you were actually using like these
style press ads, they're going to come
for you. So, operationally they are a
pain unless you want to pay for extra
rights. So, F tier. Don't really bother
doing this one anymore unless you get
those rights. Very similar though to the
press ads is the breaking news ad,
right? And this is what I feel like
performance marketers were forced to do
because press became so unreliable, and
every time we would put up these press
ads, these publications would come for
us. So, this one again can be a good
supporting cast member, but not even
that well. So, I'm going to put it as D
tier. It's been a minute since I've seen
this one crank. I'll often see it get a
few sales, but [music] it's generally
not going to be the one that's going to
transform your business overnight. And
then next up we have the tweet [music]
and Reddit ads. Now, this is one that I
often find is really good for a brand
that's spending anywhere from 100k to
maybe 250k. So, not really those big $1
million budgets, but in this range when
you don't have a ton of creative help or
creative capacity and velocity, this is
one of those statics that I have seen
show up in the top eight of several
brands operating at that level. But
again, good supporting cast member,
likely to not be the thing that scales
and cranks for your brand. Although I
will say that I used to use this a lot
as a first frame in video and that is
still working cuz I've tested that
across a few brands recently. So, maybe
just the first frame would be a B. And
then testimonial statics E. F for the
way that most of you are making them
though. These are just simply
testimonials slapped on a static and I
would say that most marketers are very
bad at them unless they are using those
super special golden nugget
testimonials, but I'm going to be very
honest, it has been a hot [music] minute
since I have seen a single testimonial
ad do anything noteworthy or worthwhile.
So, F. And then we have the listicles.
I'm going to put this [music] one as a E
actually, just a little bit better. This
is one that I got a few hits out of at a
very specific point in time, maybe like
a year or two ago and I remember making
videos about it, but it has not done
jack lately. So, this one lower on
my tier list. [music] And then we have
headline ads. I could wax romantic about
headline ads because I feel like they're
the OG of advertising, especially from
the print era, right? This is one that
if you have amazing messaging can fit
firmly in that B tier, but I find that
though a lot of the ways that most e-com
marketers are doing it is diabolical
like this or just, you know, kind of
boring like this. But again, when
combined with call outs can crush and I
have seen brands who have really nailed
their messaging and really know how to
use messaging as the hook and as the
thing that really invites people in can
crank. Ooh, and then we have statistics.
I feel like if you've watched this
channel for a while, you will recognize
this ad. I have shown it ad nauseam, but
this is another one that I'm going to be
ranking a little lower as a C tier. Now,
I've actually seen this work pretty well
for like big luxury brands that have
retail presence. But this is one that if
you are a D2C or e-com only brand, it's
likely not going to scale becoming your
top eight at motion. But, if you're
operating more on like brand awareness
or even traffic, this is one where,
okay, for those higher funnel like
objectives, this one can often be the
one that gets the best performance. But,
if you're trying to make an ROI directly
from Meta, likely not going to be the
one to do it for you. Ooh, and then we
have the OG classic S versus them. I'm
going to give you a B. This is one that
even though I kind of roll my eyes every
time a team member puts it forward, I'm
like,
"Is it going to work?" And it does. It
can often go into the top eight on our
motion reports. But, it's one that I
find is really just getting that like
mid-funnel audience. So, it's likely not
going to be the unicorn ad that is going
to scale your brand. Ooh, partnership
ads. Can I give this one an S tier? I'm
going to give it an S tier. Partnership
ads, when you have the right creator,
and hell, maybe you even tested out
their content before before you decided
to do partnership ads. This is [music]
the thing that is making or breaking
brands on Meta right now. If you are not
doing partnership ads, regardless of
where you're at in your scale, [music]
and you are bringing a butter knife to a
gunfight. And I have said that exact
line in other videos. Partnership ads
are so, so vital to Meta's performance
right now for a few reasons. Number one,
because [music] the Andromeda algorithm
is a persona-based algorithm, one of the
best ways to actually reach your
personas are to do that through creators
who your personas are actively engaging
with and loving. Additionally, if you
are a brand that is spending
multi-million dollars per month on the
platform, this is one of the best ways
to actually reach net [music] new
audiences. So, you have to make sure
that you're looking at your rolling
reach month over month. And if you see
that going down, partnership ads are a
really great way to get new reach and to
reach new people. Because the seed
audience from partnership ads is
actually starting from the creators own
audience. So, partnership ads are the
number one thing that I would be
investing [music]
in as a brand over the next few months
on Meta. Hell, for the rest of the year,
really. You really need to dial in on
your creator program. And if you're
trying to understand how to work with
higher caliber [music] creators and
influencers, I actually just came out
with a video last week that really dives
in to how to develop your creator
program. So, that's one [music] that I
would take a look at. And then we have
the hot girl Instagram stories. This ad
is exactly what [music] it says. How
does a hot girl take Instagram stories?
She's taking pictures of herself in a
mirror. She's taking selfies. She's
doing flat lays, right? These ones,
again, really good supporting cast.
[music] So, I would say B tier, but I
just find a lot of brands are like
cannot execute them. They need to work
with more hot girls to get this done, to
[music] be honest. Ooh, and then very
similarly, creator low-fi statics. I'm
going to put this one for firmly in the
B tier. This is another really good
supporting cast member. In fact, another
hint that I'll give you guys is when you
are contracting creators to make
partnership ads, also have them do a few
low-fi creator statics, essentially how
they would do stories for the brand.
This is something that really, really
works well and develops a little bit of
a funnel system for that specific
creator. It's like my number one tip for
partnership ads right now. And then we
have authority ads. I'm going to put
this one as a SRA SRA. I'm going to put
it as an A. Authority ads, especially
for hyper-competitive niches, like
supplements or beauty. Being able to
work with someone who is an authority in
the space, like a doctor or a
dermatologist or whatever, is something
that is going to be able to give you
that higher-level validation and trust,
so that people can get over the hump of
the objections that they have to buying
your brand. Plus, it is a really great
way to add creative diversity into your
account instead of just rinsing and
reusing the same UGC playbook. [music]
And then 27, we have celebrity ads. I
wanted to include this one because I
actually used to do celebrity briefing
for a big nine-figure brand and I'm
going to put this one in the C-tier.
Wow, I have seen it crank with specific
creators or celebrities, but I've also
seen it not quite get great performance
from a lot
>> [laughter]
>> of the celebrities that I've worked
with. And I think there's a few reasons
for this, right? Like, if you want to
understand the difference between an
influencer and a celebrity, actually be
sure to watch that other video that I
just did about building your creator
program. I really go deep into that and
I think that is vital to understanding
why creators and celebrities can be a
massive unlock for your brand, but can
also be a big money pit. And then next
up, we have objection handling ads. This
is going to be another one that's going
to be B-tier. Another great one to
really help flush out more of that
middle funnel and get more conversions.
And I also find that this is one that
can start to work pretty quickly [music]
because if you were developing great top
of funnel content, you really understand
your personas. If you are not actively
[music] answering, "Hey, we see the
concerns that you have. Here's why you
should still buy anyways." or "Here's
why you have a misconception about this
objection." This is one of those that I
find [music] often can easily rank in
the top 15 of top performers. Ooh, and
then we have podcast ads. Hot take, I'm
going to put this as an F-tier. I find
that this one is often a waste of time
right now, especially if you are hiring
out the podcast studio. I did see this
one work a number of years ago or like
really over the last 18 months, but
recently when we've tested it, it's
required a really big budget or a big AI
budget cuz yeah, we've generated these
in Higgs Field, but I just do not see
these moving the needle and becoming top
performing unicorn ads anymore unless it
is a founder who is on an actual
well-known podcast. [music] And then we
have the founder's letter static. I am
going to put this one as a B tier.
Again, this one can really crank when
it's used during a sale period, but this
one is not going to be the [music] one
that like becomes your top performing
scaling unicorn ad in that number one
slot. And then we have your AI avatar
ads. Ooh, this is a little bit
controversial. I am going to put this
one in a C tier with some really big
caveats. I have seen it become the top
performing scaling winning ad for
brands. And yes, even when we are
putting those legal disclaimers, which
we now need to do. But this is one that
I do suspect is going to start to
potentially phase out. I find that a lot
of brands are starting to make a stance
on we're going to use AI avatars or
we're not. And I actually find that the
bigger the brand, the more that they're
likely to decide that they're going to
work with creators. And I think that's
going to be a trend that trickles down.
And then we have your conversation ads.
I am going to put this one solidly in
the B tier because my goodness, it is
really hard to get creators to execute
on this one, but when done well, can
really perform for brands. And all that
this one is is really two people having
a conversation or multiple people having
a conversation, right? Could be that
podcast ad, but is a little bit more
behind the scenes [music] in nature. And
then next up we have your educational
infographics. [music] This is one that I
am going to put in the B tier. I'm
afraid that I'm putting a lot of these
in B tier because there's so much nuance
with all these different formats. This
is what I find a lot of brands don't do,
[music] but can be an excellent
supporting cast member for some of your
big creative ideas that you're already
getting performance out of in the ad
account. And again, what I love about it
too, is that it masquerades as
educational content and not an ad. So,
if you can figure out some type of chart
or infographic, this is one that I would
try to implement sooner rather than
later. Next up, we have mood board ads.
This is another B-tier one for me.
Again, it's often not going to be the
unicorn scale to the moon ad, but this
is a really good one to test
specifically for apparel, I've found.
Because if you think about it, a lot of
the fashion girlies are making these
organically. And if you find that that
content is already being consumed by
your personas naturally, then this is a
really good one to test. [music] And
then 37, we have your AI billboard ads.
I'm going to put this as a D. Have we
done a D ranking yet? This is one that I
find has just been so overdone. It's so
cheesy. I have not seen it perform for
any of my accounts personally over the
last few months, but I do have a number
of creative strategist friends,
specifically in supplements and health
and wellness, that say if you can like
use really punchy language, taboo
language, then this can work really
well. But I just personally haven't seen
it. And then 38, we have your ugly ads
or your handwriting ads. This one can
still perform really well. And you know
what? Hot take, but I haven't seen a ton
of creative strategists putting forth
this idea lately. Probably because it's
overdone. But where I often see it crush
is especially for sales period. So, I
always try to make sure, hey, like let's
get some of those posted note ads into
rotation when we're doing a sale.
Similarly, [music]
especially for sales, are going to be
your warehouse ads. Now, Zach [music]
Stuck over at Hollow Socks does
excellent warehouse ads, so does Oats
Overnight. And then, of course, we have
more [music] of your behind-the-scenes,
getting ready to sell out type of
warehouse ads. I think these do really,
really well, but I'm going to put them
firmly in the C-tier because often times
when I've actually gone to make content
in warehouses, it's a very different
experience than like what I want to be
in an ad. So, I find that these can be a
little bit operationally complex. And
they're very often not in the top five
of, you know, ad winners and not going
to be the thing that really scales up an
ad account [music] anymore unless you
are combining it with a founder's ad.
And then we have your street interview
ads. I'm going to put these in a C. Have
I seen them perform? Yes. Are they my
least favorite ad creative to personally
make on this planet? Yes, they are such
a to go out and make. I've [music]
filmed them in Miami, I filmed them in
New York, and wow, they are so painful.
I've actually found [music] often times
the better way to do these is to fake
them. Ooh, and then we have your VSLs,
your video sales letter. This is another
one I'm going to firmly put into the S
tier. If you are an advertiser who
really wants to develop their craft,
learn to write excellent VSLs,
especially [music]
for health and wellness and fitness and
anything that really needs a lot of
upfront education. VSLs are top tier for
getting not only the trust of your
audience, but also getting them to
convert. And then we have the green
screen commentary ads. I feel like I'm
doing this one solely for myself cuz I
do a lot of these ads, but this is
something I've also seen work really,
really well in apparel. So, I'm going to
put this one as an A tier, especially if
you're combining it with more of an
educational angle. Ooh, and then we have
your comment reply ads, especially if
you have a certain objection or you have
a frequently asked question that keeps
[music] on popping up. This is one that
again can do a lot of movement in your
middle and lower funnel, but likely
isn't going to be the one that's going
to scale to the moon unless you're
really specifically making that question
a lot more top of funnel. I'm going to
put it as a B tier. And then we have
your notes app and your UX ads. Man, oh
man, do these take up a lot of time and
bandwidth [music] and show up on a lot
of gurus' reels and YouTube's, but they
do not convert, y'all. F tier. I
think these UX ads, they're really bad
at getting the right people to stop
because they look familiar, so they
initially make everyone stop. So, I
think it just confuses the algorithm.
So, like as low as it can go, not it.
Ooh, and then we have your catalog ads
and your DPA ads. I'm going to put this
in an A tier. If you can get a really
good catalogs ad system going,
especially if you can work with
different templates and different
creatives within your DPA. Contrary to
popular belief, it's not just going to
target your middle and lower funnel and
just like act as retargeting. It can go
more dynamic ads broad audience DABA. I
don't even know if we're still using
that language anymore. It can go a lot
more top-of-funnel, but I find a lot of
brands are just not properly utilizing
their catalog ads, but catalog ads are
actually a current top performer for one
of my clients because they figured out
how to make it work for a cold
prospecting audience. Ooh, and then we
have carousel ads. I am going to put
this as an E tier. This one is more of a
waste of time than anything, right? The
thing that pains me about catalog ads is
like there's actually quite a lot of
inventory for it because not many brands
are doing them, but what I have found
really challenging about them is that
it's really hard to know the right story
to tell [music] with catalog ads.
>> I've been able to make a few top
performers, especially when it comes to
showing different bundles or even
putting a slideshow of like the top
performing static ads. That's a hack
that you can do. But, this is one where
the juice isn't often worth the squeeze
because you are making multiple assets
to be in this carousel and you don't
even know if it's going to convert. Ooh,
and then we have your duet
reaction/stitch
style ads. [music] And this is one that
I find is great for founders content and
I don't see a lot of founders doing this
type of ad. However, you do have to get
rights from the original creator to even
have their face show up in an ad and
activate [music] on paid social. So
actually maybe I'm going to put this one
in C. I'm going to put it in C cuz it's
a little bit operationally complex. We
have been able to essentially fake this
initial like reaction reel or the reel
they're doing the reaction to with AI or
with another creator. But sometimes it
just needs to be the real thing and we
have actually reached out to those
original creators and gotten usage
rights for them for very low cost or for
free. But this is one that convert
really well, become in [music] the top
five, but often is going to be
challenging to make. And then we have
your ASMR ads for specific industries.
ASMR ads really crush. Like think the
pet industry for [music] instance,
beauty. But I find that you really have
to work with specific ASMR creators to
make this really perform. But I don't
often find it's the scale the moon
unicorn winning ad. So I'm going to put
it in the C tier. [music] And then we
have your regular run of the mill UGC,
right? Think mass application UGC or UGC
coming from TikTok shop, taking what's
working there, putting that into the ad
account. Yeah, creator content is still
crushing. But I find that even with the
brands that I'm talking to that have
these massive creator programs, it's
often a lot of volume with only a few
things hitting per week. And I notice
that there is a general fatigue on like
problem-solution oriented UGC [music]
content, especially when it has a
voiceover and a b-roll and it just feels
very manufactured. So like thinking
about that type of UGC, I'm going to put
it in the C tier. Ooh, and then we have
a get ready with me day in my life. This
obviously is a lot more popular on
organic, but I do see a number of briefs
coming down the pipeline from brands and
I see it out there in the ether with
this type of content being activated
[music] on paid. This is one that I
often find does not scale super well on
paid unless you are working with a
really specific type of creator and your
product can really comes in the morning
early in their day or their routine. So
I'm going to put this one in a D tier.
And then the final one is what I'm going
to call the challenging your beliefs
format. This one I love because it's not
too operationally complex. As long as
you have some great B roll in your ad
library, you can likely make this piece
of content. I'm going to put this as a B
because as long as you know what the
limiting beliefs of your core personas
are, you can make this type of format.
And I've seen it perform again and again
across industries, [music] across
clients. Woo! That was 51 ads ranking.
And I feel like I just yapped for God,
like 30 minutes. I hope that was
interesting for y'all. I don't know if
I'll ever do that again. I'll talk to
you next week. Love you. Bye.
>> [music]
[music]